which were the segments that it largely
came
from in the first place uh seasons
greetings to all of you and to all of
your viewers uh so if you look at from
an i Lombard standpoint I think what we
have been talking through is uh growth
seems to be coming back and that's
exactly is indicative of what you
rightly mentioned I think even this
quarter we have had an outperformance
related to the industry growth we had a
growth of 17% industry growth in quarter
2 was 10%
um largely I would the growth has
stemmed from couple of key preferred
segments for us one is health and the
other is the commercial lines portfolio
which pans across fire engineering
Marine cargo liability and so on and so
forth in so far as motor is concerned I
think we still look at the segment to be
a little more competitive uh hopefully
we should see aggression getting played
out over the next few quarters but
primarily in this quarter a large part
of the growth is driven as I said from
health and the commercial lines
portfolio and within that I think the
health retail segment which is an area
where we have been investing in
expanding distribution that has done
exceedingly well for us when you look at
quarter two numbers on individual or
retail Health that number is about
15.8% but just for the month of
September we have actually grown at
about 21% which is in fact faster than
even the Standalone Health companies
which have grown at 90% so all in all I
think a great quarter for us in terms of
growth and the momentum looks quite
positive as we look
forward to us about premiums across
segments because we've seen a phenomenal
growth in crop premiums up a solid 322
per on year that's followed by Health
marine motor premiums have remained a
little bit soft can you give us more
insights and walk us through what your
key Focus areas are going
forward so let me address the last part
first I think if you ask me in terms of
her preferred segments at an aggregate
or maybe at a broader level it will
continue to be focus on motor health and
the commercial lines uh portfolio as
such those will clearly be areas of
opportunities as we see even in terms of
the way forward now within that if I
were to kind of break down each of those
portfolios let me take up the health
piece first uh as we all know Health has
primarily three segments so far as
individual health and the employer
employee portfolios are concerned and
then of course we have the government
sponsored Mass health programs um in so
far as is Lombard is concerned which is
what I was just mentioning I think we
have been continuing to look at
expanding the retail Health distribution
franchise and extremely happy to note as
I mentioned uh just earlier I think the
growth on that is looking extremely
positive for us so hence that is one key
driver of growth in this quarter as well
and we are extremely kind of looking
forward to similar maintaining similar
levels of growth as we head into the
subsequent quarters on the retail Health
franchise even corporate or employee
employee employer employee portfolio is
doing quite well for us even there again
we had we have kind of exceeded or
rather outperformed the industry numbers
uh significantly and that will again
continue to be an area of opportunity as
we look forward and when you look at uh
the group health portfolio it comprises
of one what I just mentioned which is
the employer employee segment and the
second is a business that we do through
tie-ups with various financial
institutions that could be Banks that
could be uh nbfcs housing finance
companies and so on and so forth and
given fact that there is clearly an
increased levels of disbursements that
are happening with each of this
institutional TI ups that is also aiding
significant growth on the group health
portfolio which is other than the
employer employee segment so that's
again kind of doing quite well for us uh
to your point on crop uh you are
absolutely right crop is definitely ly
seen a meaningful increase in the
overall numbers but having said that
what we have been talking through is
when you look at it more on an annual
basis the extent of Premium contribution
of crop to the overall revenues is
expected to be within uh the threshold
of the 5% number that we have spoken
about okay but um Health has continued
to remain in Focus as well especially
with health premiums which have seen a
healthy run rate in Q2 as well help us
understand how Trends are shaping up
when it comes to the health vertical is
there a lateral impact of inflation in
the
space no that's a very part of the
question is very interesting and maybe I
will address it separately but coming
back to your growth point I think as we
all know um maybe thanks uh to covid or
even otherwise Health as a segment is
significantly underpenetrated when you
look at retail Health penetration in
particular it's a single digit single
digit penetration is what we have as a
country as a whole which has roughly
close to let's say 1 .3 or 1.4 billion
people and therefore the opportunity in
that segment is significantly humongous
and that's an area from an is standpoint
I think we have been as I said investing
in expanding distribution and uh product
portfolio expansion as well uh so hence
the opportunity is immense and again
thanks to covid maybe the pace of
acceleration is far more faster and
today possibly when you talk to a lot of
people everyone is talking about one
either to need either the need to have a
health insurance cover or even for the
ones who had a health insurance cover
they're looking for making sure that
that coverage is adequate so that gives
us an opportunity for
maybe the extent of incremental coverage
that one can take in so far as health
insurance coverages are concerned uh so
overall I think U that's an area where
definitely one sees a lot of potential
in terms or maybe room for growth and
that's where I as I mentioned we have
been investing one in expanding
Distribution on the agency front two we
have from an isar standpoint we have
been significantly also embarking on uh
promoting our IL take care app
proposition now that's something which
we have seen uh excellent uh outcomes in
the form of downloads that we have seen
particularly in this quarter I mean on
year-to day basis I mean as on September
we have almost close to 2.7 million
downloads of which close to almost 1
million downloads is what we had seen uh
in this particular water uh so again we
are quite extremely excited with the way
how things have played out on the IL
take care app platform and overall I
think the growth momentum and the growth
opportunity the health side is extremely
positive and that's a segment where Isis
Lombard is significantly investing on to
your second point on are we seeing any
element of Health inflation absolutely I
mean that's something that we have been
talking
through okay and your combined ratio is
nearly stable on a year-on-year basis
can we expect it to Trend downwards from
here on also if you can throw some color
on the claims ratio as well what's the
status now um give us the Insight when
it comes to Total claims
picture so maybe let me answer the first
part uh uh so you point on combined
ratios yes absolutely I think that is a
directional effort that isard is looking
at uh even at the time which was this
couple of years back what we had
indicated when we announced transaction
of integration with bti AA we did
indicate that uh combin ratios will stay
elevated for a couple of years once we
get all regulatory approvals in place uh
and two uh and that's kind of played out
very well in so far as the completion of
is concerned uh secondly what we had
also indicated is we would obviously
want to stay invested in uh building our
digital distribution build our retail
health agency distribution and obviously
try to create excellence in customer
service and uh related capabilities what
happens when you are in the path of
expansion of distribution whether it is
health agency or whether it is digital
all of these costs come to you up front
whereas the benefit in the form of
revenues will play out over a period of
time because as distribu distribution
starts to scale up you will obviously
see incremental revenues getting played
out in so far as Top Line growth is
concerned so hence to that extent is
what we had indicated at least for the
next couple of years which is the
current year as well as for the next
year we will continue to see maybe
combined ratios stay a little elevated
closer to closer to about 104% or
thereabout and thereafter obviously we
would want to see a declining slope in
so far as the combined ratio uh outcomes
are concerned uh so hence U the traj
combined is something that we would
obviously want to see an improvement and
that's what we are kind of working
towards in terms of uh efficiency and uh
productivity just to give a small data
point in terms of how things have played
out not just for one year over the last
14 years our growth in profit after tax
has compounded at almost close to
20% uh so that's obviously and our head
count productivity uh efficiency is
something that again over the similar
period we would have seen a headcount
productivity efficiency of almost close
to 15% kager over the last 14e cycle so
that's clearly an area where we
significantly invest on and some of the
investment as I said currently is
obviously getting expensed upfront once
the revenues get played out over the
next couple of years we should be able
to see a declining trajectory on the
combin rtio fund
thank you for taking time out and
walking us through your growth
parameters that's the word from ICICI
Lombard they've